NIRAJ CHAVAN UI / Web Developer

Email - nirajd327@gmail.com **Phone** - +91 96071 95436

Splendour Greens Seetai Lake, 202, C Wing, Mulshi Road, Opposite Heera Garden, Bhugaon, Pune 412115

Portfolio - https://niraj-chavan.herokuapp.com/

Linkedin - https://in.linkedin.com/in/niraj-chavan-8267bb98

CAREER SUMMARY

UI Developer with 4.10 years of experience in designing, developing, and managing complex e-commerce sites.

An energetic and imaginative young Web Developer who is able to work alongside other talented IT professionals in creating websites to the very highest standards.

Skilled in developing and achieving technical objectives and goals to support the organization vision while managing & developing projects of web application.

EXPERIENCE

SENIOR UI ENGINEER, XPANXION INTERNATIONAL PVT. LTD.

Jan 2017 – Present, Location – Pune Implementation of angular custom reusable components, JWT token implementation, performance optimization and API integration.

UI DEVELOPER, CONNECT | 91 WEB SOLUTIONS PVT. LTD.

Dec 2015 - Jan 2017, Location – Pune
UI enhancement designs for better user experience,
convert PSD into HTML and make the websites
compatible with all browsers.

WEB DEVELOPER, WHITECODE IT SOLUTION

July 2014 - Dec 2015, Location – Pune Responsible for participating in the full life cycle of new website development and maintaining best practice procedures in all areas of work.

SKILLS

WEB TECHNOLOGIES –

HTML5, CSS, SASS, Bootstrap 4, JavaScript, JQuery, Typescript, Angular 2/5/7, JSON, WordPress, Python, Flask, JHipster

VERSION CONTROL TOOLS -

SVN, GIT

DATABASE -

MySQL, PostgreSQL

PROJECT TRACKING TOOLS -

Jira, Rally, Zoho, Trello

BUILD TOOL -

Webpack, NPM, Bower

TESTING FRAMEWORK TOOLS –

Karma, Jasmine, Jest

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING (COMPUTER ENGINEERING)

Dr. D. Y. Patil Institute of Engineering & Technology, Pune University July 2011 – June 2014

DIPLOMA IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING

Y. B. Patil Polytechnic, Akurdi, Pune (Maharashtra State Board of Technical Education)

July 2008 - May 2011

SECONDRY SCHOOL EDUCATION

Sharada Vidyamandir, Maharashtra Board June 2007 – July 2008

PERSONAL DETAILS

DATE OF BIRTH: 07 August 1992

MARITAL STATUS: Unmarried

NATIONALITY: Indian

PERMANENT ADDRESS:

At - Post - Tivare, Pali – Khopoli Rd, Taluka - Sudhagad, District - Raigad, Maharashtra, Pin Code - 410205

LANGUAGE KNOWN:

English, Marathi, Hindi

PROJECT DETAILS -

Team Size – 2

Project Name – K7 SECURITY (Xpanxion) Role - Senior UI Engineer Skills used – HTML 5, CSS, Bootstrap 4, Angular 7, Typescript, Karma, Jasmine, JHipster Framework Team Size - 8 Project Name - SCOPERETAIL (Xpanxion) Role - UI Engineer Skills used – HTML 5, SASS, Bootstrap 4, Angular 5, Typescript, Karma, Jasmine Team Size - 22 Project Name - ADA Accessibility (Xpanxion) Role – UI Engineer Skills used – HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, Require JS, Django, Python, PostgreSQL, Docker for Windows Team Size - 18 Project Name - HOLLAND AMERICA LINE (https://www.hollandamerica.com/) (Xpanxion) Role - UI Engineer Skills used – HTML5, SCSS, JavaScript, JQuery, Angular 2, Bootstrap 3, Git, Rally, Team Size - 6 **Project Name -** CERTASLIM (https://www.certaslim.com/) (Connect | 91) Role - UI Developer Skills used – HTML5, SCSS, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Angular JS, Git, Jira Team Size - 4 Project Name – UITBIEDEN (https://www.uitbieden.nl/) (Connect | 91) Role - UI Developer Skills used – HTML 5, SCSS, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap 3, Bitbucket, Zoho Team Size - 4 Project Name - VIDEOTIER (https://www.videotier.com/) (Connect | 91) Role - UI Developer Skills used – HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, PHP, SASS, Bootstrap, Photoshop Team Size - 6 Project Name - VARUN DESHMUKH & CO. (http://ddca.net.in/) (WhiteCode) Role – Web Developer Skills used – PHP, WordPress, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap

Project Name - SAISUKAMAL (http://www.saisukamal.com/) (WhiteCode) Skills used – PHP, WordPress, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap Team Size – 3

Role - Web Developer

NIRAJ CHAVAN PLACE - PUNE